<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nature and Human</title>
    <link>https://zian999.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nature and Human</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zian999.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use Lightroom Classic only as a DAM tool for FREE</title>
      <link>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2021/20210608-use-lightroom-as-dam-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2021/20210608-use-lightroom-as-dam-for-free/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: After your adobe lightroom subscription ends, you still have access to all your local photos, and use all the modules except for the Develop and Map modules. This means you can still import new photos and manage all your photos with Lightroom&amp;rsquo;s tagging, keyword, filter and even quick develop functions, which makes it possible to use LrC as a standalone DAM (digital asset management) software and leave complex editing tasks to other dedicated softwares like GIMP and Capture NX-D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Chinese character tool - translate to Pinyin and extract radical</title>
      <link>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2021/20210330-chinese-character-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2021/20210330-chinese-character-tool/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I have the need to translate large amount of Chinese characters to Pinyins and extract the corresponding radicals. Recently I found this js library &amp;lsquo;cnchar&amp;rsquo; which exactly meets my need. Using the library I created this page for convience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve the connection problem of Smart Keyboard (not recognized by iPad Pro)</title>
      <link>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2020/20200402-solve_connection_problem_of_smart_keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 18:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2020/20200402-solve_connection_problem_of_smart_keyboard/</guid>
      <description>I purchased the Smart Keyboard for my iPad Pro 10.5 on the first day it was available. It worked well for about 2 years and I don’t remember from when it suddenly stopped working. Nothing happens if I connect it to my iPad. After some googling I found that this seems to be a common problem encountered by other Smart Keyboard owners. But no reliable solutions to this problem can be found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update local lensfun database for Darktable</title>
      <link>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2020/20200228-update_local_lensfun_database/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 21:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2020/20200228-update_local_lensfun_database/</guid>
      <description>I just give up using Lightroom.
Because I had to reinstall my system after Christmas, so I choose to try and install Manjaro along with the OEM Windows10. Taking this opportunity, I spent some time transfered all my photo collections from Lightroom 6 to Darktable.
The darktable used Lensfun library to perform lens correction. Lensfun have collected a lot of lens and camera data. By now (2020-02-28) there&amp;rsquo;re 1057 lenses in the database, and all the popular cameras are covered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get p-values for effects/variables from (g)lmer models</title>
      <link>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2019/lrt_pvalues_for_glmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 19:29:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2019/lrt_pvalues_for_glmer/</guid>
      <description>For some reason (see GLMM FAQ and here for more detail), the lmer function in the lme4 package doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide p-values for the coefficients (i.e., whether the betas you got are different from 0 or not).
If you use lme4::glmer, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that there are p-values listed in the summary of the model. However, I found two problems of them.
  First, those p-values are testing the significance of the coefficients of the linear model, not the effects of our idependent variables (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a new lens profile to (ceased) Lightroom 6</title>
      <link>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2019/add_new_lens_profile_to_lr6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2019/add_new_lens_profile_to_lr6/</guid>
      <description>The Lightroom 6 was killed by Adobe in 2017 and will never get updates any more. For people (like me) who don&amp;rsquo;t want to subscribe to Adobe&amp;rsquo;s plans and are sticking with LR6, I found a way to add new lens profiles to LR6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birding in Point Pelee National Park</title>
      <link>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2019/point_pelee_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zian999.github.io/posts/2019/point_pelee_2019/</guid>
      <description>Two week ago, we went to the Point Pelee National Park to watch the migrating birds (mainly warblers). It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful experience. We saw a lot of birds that we have never seen before in local area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
